Reviewer: Tanya Cushman
So, I have a little test for you.
Don't panic.
I'm not here to judge you.
It's just a little test, OK?
to memorize 10 words in the right order.
to write down what you remembered.
to check your answers.
So, are you guys ready?
Well, we're going to start anyway.
So,
in the right order in 30 seconds
in three, two, one, go!
OK. Stop.
Now write down what you remember.
OK, and stop.
Now quickly check your answers.
a lot of grunting and moaning.
you out too much.
Now a moment of reflection.
I'd like you to ask yourself,
and was it the best way to do it?"
of my parents and grandparents,
was an absolutely essential skill.
want to remember a list of anything?
and you're done, right?
has somehow become less important.
in today's day and age,
still want to get better at memorizing?
I'd like to tell you a little story.
In high school, I flunked a grade, twice.
I finally got my diploma.
Sweet, sweet freedom!
What would I do with it?
I didn't know.
One thing I did know, however,
to go back to school
because that old learning business,
it wasn't cut out for me.
to sunny California for nine months,
not beggar - bagger.
So in a supermarket,
and then I'd get a little tip.
Surprisingly, that year I learned so much.
of groceries really, really quickly.
I learned how to drive a car.
And in California,
than they are in Amsterdam.
a little chat with a stranger,
just for the hell of it.
that I don't hate learning,
just the specific way of doing it.
So I decided to go and study psychology.
Now for the first time ever,
that I absolutely wanted to know.
more time in the library
as a teenager, voluntarily.
spending all of my time in the library
because I'd never learned how to learn.
with different methods of reading texts,
of memorizing texts,
of three hours per chapter down to one.
enabled me to do an honors program,
to get my degree,
and to fall in love with learning.
for a company called Remind,
the science and art of learning.
what we ourselves missed.
Now for the past three years,
the Dutch National Memory Championships
for high schoolers.
is capable of amazing feats of memory,
but also to show that memorization
your French or your Spanish words.
to share this with you.
So, in the beginning,
I made you do this little test,
of how you're memorizing things right now.
a new type of memory experience.
This time you can even sit back and relax.
to find a comfortable position to sit,
and to take a deep breath.
of someone you know called John,
and I want you to see him.
out of the sky,
and he just threw it on your feet.
really big and red and swollen
threw the sun on your feet.
Now you look to your knees,
10 little guys playing basketball -
very strange sight.
And on their shirts,
colored letters the "New York Knicks,"
so you have some Knicks on your knees.
Next, you look to where your thighs are,
but they're gone.
with Fords, the cars.
or Ford Mustangs.
Your thighs have been replaced with Fords.
Now, with your bottom,
of a go-kart vibrating.
the hard plastic seat of a go-kart.
Your belly starts rumbling very loudly.
and it leads you to McDonald's,
starts shooting rays of light at you
with a ray gun.
at you with a ray gun.
He hits you on your chest,
a big bush of gray hairs is growing.
is growing from your chest.
to shave it off,
and on your doormat, you see a letter.
So you open it and it has good news.
falling off your shoulders.
A huge weight falling off your shoulders.
because you just paid all of your bills.
Big bills, little bills,
and you have plenty of money to spare.
Now you proceed to the bathroom,
because now on your neck,
of thin blonde hairs have appeared.
of thin blonde hair.
As you look in the mirror,
just starts talking all by itself,
yes we can; yes we can."
and now suddenly your eyes are, ah,
just poked out both of your eyes
with a trumpet made of pure gold.
and come back to this place.
than where you just came from.
So, I just made you guys memorize
of the United States of America
in the right order.
Now I'm going to show you,
how many of these you still know.
to ask you what happened there,
and then you could think of it.
if you just shout it out.
Now, what happened to your feet?
President Johnson.
(Laughter)
Knicks, yes - President Nixon.
replaced with?
Fords - President Ford.
with your bottom?
OK, President Carter, yes.
Some people are ahead of the game.
Now, your belly led you to McDonald's;
what happened?
OK. Ronald McDonald shooting rays of …
So Ronald Reagan.
He hits in your chest, and you got what?
Big bush of gray hairs - Bush senior.
(Laughter)
Now, your shoulders got light, why?
Paid all your bills - Bill Clinton.
Now, what did you have on your neck?
OK, a bush of thin blonde hairs.
Bush junior.
What was your mouth saying?
"Yes we can" - President Obama.
And what happened to your eyes?
Yeah, Donald Duck, trumpet, pure gold.
Who else but Donald Trump?
than the first time, please stand up.
everyone standing up;
that's awesome.
is more fun than the last way you used,
if you're already standing.
Oh whoa, now we almost have everyone.
I'm very pleased to see this.
OK. You guys can sit back down.
Thank you very much.
bizarre images to memorize,
suddenly it becomes a lot easier.
to a place you know well,
like your body,
becomes a lot easier.
OK. Well, cool.
But I asked you guys in the beginning,
"Why should we, in today's day and age,
at this - at memorizing?"
in a skill like this,
at a different skill:
the skill of experimentation.
methods of doing things,
get better at anything.
for me and what doesn't.
the skill of experimentation?
I may have never gone back to school;
studying psychology,
have been standing here today,
I really couldn't do was public speaking.
not doing things that they might love,
that they might even be great at
because they think they can't do it.
So how beautiful would it be
that they can get better at anything,
at getting better at things, get it?
But not just the kids,
is often seen as too old to learn.
But they're not too rusty.
by experimenting,
and I hope you experienced that today.
Now at Remind,
of experimentation into three steps:
and the experiment.
of what you're doing right now.
you became aware of the fact
the words over and over
and that that doesn't work too well.
The second step:
to new possibilities and trying them out.
So maybe during the visualization,
or at least you like it more.
And the third step is the experiment.
from that new experience that you had
to see how it works for you.
So, maybe you're one of those people
introduces themselves to you,
you just immediately forget their name.
Yeah, sound familiar?
to do something about that.
through the first two steps.
The final step is up to you.
I'd like you to take a moment for yourself
on the little card we've given you
in your wallet as a reminder.
these steps of experimentation,
you discover what you're doing;
to new possibilities,
to continually transform.
And regardless of what you're learning,
or martial arts or mathematics,
that you're trying to develop,
at the process of learning itself.
And that's something that sticks.
to your new job, your new hobby,
your new relationship, your new whatever.
absolutely everyone should know,
teach it in schools.
to be implemented in schools.
change starts with the individual.
It starts with you.
So, go out there and experiment.
Learn something new
or a new way of approaching something old
as valuable as the art of learning.
Thank you.
(Applause)